Guide to the Joe Conzo, Jr. photographs and ephemera, 1977-present.
Conzo, Joe, Jr. photographs and ephemera,
- Series I. Photographs
  - 4 x 6 Prints - Bronx, N.Y. Scenes
    - Joe Conzo personal photos, 1978-1982; 67 prints (Box 13, Folder 12)
      These photos depict places and people from Joe Conzo's life in the late 1970s and early 1980s. There are several self-portraits, photos of his son Angel's baptism, his ex-wife Gina Martinez, his first car (a 1976 Chevy Malibu), his cat, his apartment, Lorraine Montenegro (Joe's mother) and her boyfriend Sailor, a basement clubhouse that he shared with his friends, Joe's girlfriend Doris, Joe's family members Donnie (uncle), Eric Kane (brother), Lorraine Montenegro (mother), and Anita (aunt), Joe and friends at Coney Island, Joe's "wedding" to an unknown woman in 1981, Joe and Rolando Arroyo (son of Carmen Arroyo) at Michelangelo Apartments in 1980, and one photo from the South Bronx High School 1980 senior trip to a dude ranch in upstate New York. There are also several self-portraits (including one taken at the studio of Tom Rose Joe's mentor, at Riverside and 92nd St. in Manhattan). Also included are some of Joe's lighting experiments.
    - Contact Sheets, 1976-1983; 35 prints (Box 13, Folder 13)
      The contact sheets are numbered 1-35, but the photos are in no particular order on them. Joe's negatives were kept in a box in his grandmother's house for several years, and they were not organized before the 4x6 prints were developed.
    - Hip Hop Doc - Kool Moe Dee, Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Latin Music Friends, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Joey's Early Photographs, Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Joey, Family, and Friends, Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Series II. Contact Sheets, Negatives, and Slides, 1976-1985
  File subjects are listed out for contact sheets and negatives as labeled by Joe Conzo. Numerous unlabeled sheets are included in each case and are not listed out in the guide.
  Most contact sheets have been scanned and are available through ARTstor's Shared Shelf Commons. Item ID number ranges for each case are listed out where applicable.
  - Case A, 1979-1982
    - "Negrils" CC4 Rock St. Crew, Undated (Box 1)
    - Easter Sunday - Harlem World, Undated (Box 1)
    - Beau's Restaurant (Farewell to Charlie), 1980-01-14 (Box 1)
    - General shots urban, Undated (Box 1)
    - T-Connection, 1979 (Box 1)
    - Norman Thomas H.S. boat ride - Harlem World, Undated (Box 1)
    - Harlem World, Undated (Box 1)
    - Amityville LI, 1982 (Box 1)
    - Third Avenue Festival, Undated (Box 1)
    - Boys' Club, Undated (Box 1)
    - Studio Shoot, Undated (Box 1)
  - Case B, 1982
    - Puerto Rico, 1982-11 (Box 1)
    - Cold Crush (St. Joseph), Undated (Box 1)
    - Born in the Bronx final, Undated (Box 1)
    - Fort Apache, Paul Newman, Undated (Box 1)
    - Boys' Club and home, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Case C, Summer
    JC_CS_071 - JC_CS_107
    - General shots, school, job, 1979 (Box 1)
    - Mondale's wife, 1979 (Box 1)
    - General shots (Chicita!), 1980-01-19-1980-01-23 (Box 1)
    - General shots, fighting fire, 1980-03-09-1980-03-11 (Box 1)
    - Channel 2 and Benjie, 1982-06 (Box 1)
    - Atlantic City and Aunt Lily's birthday, Undated (Box 1)
    - Mrs. A - Channel 2/ NY Urban League, 1982-07 (Box 1)
    - Yearbook pictures and Anonetty shots, 1979-11-12-1979-11-15 (Box 1)
    - Ch. 2 Randall Pinkston LM IBJR, 1985-04 (Box 1)
    - Rolling around, 1985-04-1985-05 (Box 1)
    - Puerto Rican Day Parade, 1985-06-09 (Box 1)
    - Photos by Pete Torres - dance show, 1985-07 (Box 1)
    - Seniors, general shots, 1980-03 (Box 1)
    - Mondale's wife, Undated (Box 1)
    - General shots Myra - Yvette, Undated (Box 1)
    - General shots - school - Purchase College - school walkout, Undated (Box 1)
    - General shots (school and office), 1979-12 (Box 1)
    - General shots outside and inside, 1980-02 (Box 1)
    - Chiquista, Undated (Box 1)
    - General shots, fighting fire, 1980-03-09-1980-03-10 (Box 1)
    - Senior trip, Malibu Ranch, 1980-03-07-1980-03-09 (Box 1)
  - Binder D, 1980
    - Slides, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Case D, 1975-1980
    JC_CS_108 - JC_CS_146
    - Puerto Rico, 1979-04 (Box 1)
    - General shots of Omi and Jeny, 1979-03 (Box 1)
    - General shots of Omi and Jeny, 1975-03 (Box 1)
    - Teresa and Stacey, 1979-02 (Box 1)
    - Atlantic City H.R. c/o Roberto G., Undated (Box 1)
    - Atlantic City and general shots, Undated (Box 1)
    - Washington D.C., Undated (Box 1)
    - Randle's School, 1979 (Box 1)
    - School - Navy band, 1979 (Box 1)
    - Canada, Quebec, Spring 79 (Box 1)
    - General shots (overdeveloped), 1980-02 (Box 1)
    - General shots, 1980-03-18-1980-03-20 (Box 1)
    - Laura's birthday party at Chico East, 1980-01-26 (Box 1)
  - Case E, 1982
    JC_CS_001 - JC_CS_047
    - Mrs. A - Channel 2, 1982-07 (Box 2)
    - Wild Style, CC4 - Fantastic 5, Undated (Box 2)
    - Harlem, Undated (Box 2)
    - Norman Thomas Boat Ride - Cold Crush Brothers, 1982-06 (Box 2)
    - Harlem World, Undated (Box 2)
    - Outer Skates, Jersey City, Undated (Box 2)
    - BX River, Busy Bee, CC4, Zulu, Undated (Box 2)
    - CC4, Boys Club, Hoe Ave, Undated (Box 2)
    - Norman Thomas H.S., Undated (Box 2)
    - LBP/ Hove (Box 2)
    - Hunts Pt Palace, Undated (Box 2)
  - Case F, 1978-1983
    JC_CS_197 - JC_CS_222
    - Lisei's wedding, 1978-09-18 (Box 2)
    - Home general shots, 1982 (Box 2)
    - General shots, UBP and home, Undated (Box 2)
    - General shots around house, Undated (Box 2)
    - AHA - Activities, 1981-08-26-1981-08-28 (Box 2)
    - West Binghamton NY - Epic, 1983-02 (Box 2)
  - Case G, 1980-1981
    - Farewell to Charlie, 1980-01-11 (Box 2)
    - Beau's Restaurant (Farewell to Charlie), 1980-01-14 (Box 2)
    - Salsa Combo MSG, 1981-03-07 (Box 2)
    - Tito Puente at Lehman College, 1980-12-19 (Box 2)
  - Case H, Undated
    JC_CS_147 - JC_CS_172
    - Lehman College Tito Puente shots, Undated (Box 2)
  - Case I, 1976-1981
    JC_CS_173 - JC_CS_196
    - Senior Trip Malibu Ranch, 1980-03-07-1980-09 (Box 2)
    - CAFA (Committee Against Fort Apache) demo, 1980-04 (Box 2)
    - CAFA, 1981 (Box 2)
    - General Shots CAFA, 1980-04 (Box 2)
    - Exhibitions, 1976 (Box 2)
    - AHA - Activities, 1981-08-26-1981-08-28 (Box 2)
    - General shots - CAFA meeting, 1980-03 (Box 2)
    - Rock climbing (Project Discovery), 1980-04 (Box 2)
    - General shots, 1980-05 (Box 2)
    - General shots (some night shots), 1980-05 (Box 2)
    - Graduation shots, 1980-06-27 (Box 2)
    - General shots (Omi and Richie), 1980-06-28 (Box 2)
  - Negatives and Contact Sheets, 1982
    JC_CS_048 - JC_CS_070
    - Puerto Rico, 1982-11 (Box 2)
  - Case J (1 of 2), 1978-1998
    - Tats - Macy's Parade, Undated (Box 7)
    - CC4, Undated (Box 7)
    - Pacheco/TOW, Undated (Box 7)
    - TOW Legs/Red, Undated (Box 7)
    - Tito Puente - Brook Ave 148, 1998 (Box 7)
    - Wiwie's Steakhouse Armand Assante, Undated (Box 7)
    - Tito Puente Celebrity Smoke Out TP Rest, Undated (Box 7)
    - Tito Puente Atlantic City, Undated (Box 7)
    - Latin Quarter, 1998-07 (Box 7)
    - Tito Puente Latin Jazz Beacon Theater, Undated (Box 7)
  - Case J (2 of 2), Undated
    - Tito Puente Scholarship Cruise, Undated (Box 7)
  - Case K, Undated
    JC_CS_223 - JC_CS_253
    - Contact Sheets, Undated (Box 7)
  - Case K, Summer
    - Slides, 1980-1981 (Box 7)
  - Case L, Undated
    - Slides, Undated (Box 8)
  - Case L (Negatives), 1980
    - General nights shots of Tiny, Undated (Box 8)
    - General experiment shots, 1980-11 (Box 8)
    - John Lennon Vigil Central Park, 1980-11 (Box 8)
    - General shots (office and home), 1979-11 (Box 8)
    - D-76, Exhibition, Vicky and Co., Undated (Box 8)
    - Rock climbing (project discovery), 1980-04 (Box 8)
    - Omi, Janina, and Lillie, Undated (Box 8)
    - General outdoor shots, 1980-11 (Box 8)
    - Demo at Gemini - CAFA, 1981-02-09 (Box 8)
    - Passport photos, 1981-01-26 (Box 8)
    - Tiny and Roy Junior, 1980-12-22 (Box 8)
    - CAFA Demo - Waldorf Astoria, 1980-10-05 (Box 8)
    - CAFA demo at City Hall, 1980-03-24 (Box 8)
    - 5 Pointz, Undated (Box 8)
    - Park Jam - Moore House, Undated (Box 8)
    - RSC Anniversary 1, Undated (Box 8)
    - RSC Anniversary 2, Undated (Box 8)
    - RSC Anniversary 3, Undated (Box 8)
    - RG Florida, Undated (Box 8)
    - RG Montauk, Undated (Box 8)
    - 9/11, Undated (Box 8)
    - CC4 Rehearsal, Undated (Box 8)
  - Case M, Undated
    - Tito Puente Scholarship - Apollo Theater, Undated (Box 8)
- Series III. Related Materials, 1965-2007
  Folder 3 from box 4 is restricted to the permission of the curator.
  - Afrika Bambaataa, Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Bronx Documentary Center, Undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Clarkson yearbook, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Cold Crush Brothers, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Includes photocopies of handwritten lyrics and an unsigned copy of a 1982 contract between CC4 and Frost Belt International Recording Enterprises.
  - Daily News, 2007-11-01 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Includes article on early hip hop featuring Conzo photographs.
  - Flyers, 1980-1984 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Includes flyers for performances at T-Connection, Ecstasy Garage Disco, and Skatin' Palace.
  - Ghetto Brothers, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Letter from Joe to family, 1990-10-14 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Magazines, 1976-2007 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    Contains magazines related to latinx culture, as well as an issue of "That 70s Show: New York City in the 1970s" which includes writing and photos by Conzo.
    Young Lords
  - New York Post "Fort Apache" article, 1980; Mounted (Box 11)
    Clipping from March 25, 1980 issue of the New York Post, featuring Joe Conzo's photo of Paul Newman. Includes inscription: "UBP's first published student photographer, Joey Kane. Congratulations from the UBP Photography Workshop! - Reyes II"
  - Phoenix yearbook, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - School records, 1965-1975 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Tracy 168 prints, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Series IV. Born in the Bronx, 2007
  - Printer's proofs 1, 2007; Conzo, Joe; Kugelberg, Johan (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Printer's proofs 2, 2007; Conzo, Joe; Kugelberg, Johan (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Printer's proofs 3, 2007; Conzo, Joe; Kugelberg, Johan (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Printer's proofs 4, 2007; Conzo, Joe; Kugelberg, Johan (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Born in the Bronx draft 1, 2007; Conzo, Joe; Kugelberg, Johan (Box 6)
  - Born in the Bronx draft 2, 2007; Conzo, Joe; Kugelberg, Johan (Box 6)
  - Press clippings, 2007; Conzo, Joe; Kugelberg, Johan (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Japanese press clippings, 2007; Conzo, Joe; Kugelberg, Johan (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Press kit, 2007; Conzo, Joe; Kugelberg, Johan (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Hip hop historic sites, 2007; King, Angelo (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Prints from "The Breaks: Stylin' and Profilin'", 2007 (Box 4, Folder 8)